ARAF AL-JAMI

arafaljami1331@gmail.com ⋄ araf.aljami.me ⋄ +8801755045141 ⋄ Dhaka, Bangladesh

SUMMARY

Around 2 years of working experience as a software engineer, with a strong pursuit of problem-solving. Handson experience in building enterprise applications and maintaining best practices with OOD. Followed SOLID principles and design patterns to write clean, maintainable, and adaptive code.

SKILLS

Languages: C#, Typescript, Javascript, C/C++, Java

Specialties: .NET, .NET Core, Node js, Express, Web API, Git, IdentityServer4, Agile, Angular

Database and messaging: MongoDB, EF Core, MySQL, MassTransit, RabbitMQ, Mqtt, Azure Service

Bus.

EDUCATION

Leading University, Sylhet

September 2014 - April 2019

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

EXPERIENCE

Shohoj Limited, Dhaka

February 2020 - Present

Software Engineer, Backend

- · Refined the Nearest provider search, improving the performance up to 3x times.
- · Developed a service to provide, **Identity Access Management** service for 1+ million users.
- · Developed tools to migrate 1+ million users, from 12 different user store to 1 single consolidated user store.
- · Designed and developed, **User Access Management** system which consolidated user management for **6** different verticals to **1** single system.
- · Implemented a service, to aggregate location history data in a friendly format for the data science team.

Leading University, Sylhet

July 2020 - Present

Competitive Programming Trainer

- · Arranged and taken classes on competitive programming topics, data structures, algorithms.
- · Arranged practice contest for students.

SELISE rockin' software, Dhaka

November 2018 - January 2020

Software Engineer

- · Used Angular, AngularJS to develop Single Page Applications
- · Used Dotnet Core technologies to develop REST API.
- · Worked on multiple projects and implemented business requirements for Selise Auditing and Certification Platform.

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

Onsite Competitive Programming Contests

September 2014 - Present

- · 10th place (4th place University wise) out of **150** teams, at IUBAT ACM NCPC 2018. [link]
- · 16th place (8th place University wise) out of **120** teams, at MIST IUPC 2019

Online Competitive Programming Contests

September 2014 - Present

- · Active participant in online coding challenges on sites such as **TopCoder**, **Codeforces**.
- · Achieved Maximum Rating of 1982 (top 4%) in Codeforces. Handle: CLown1331. [link]

- · Achieved Maximum Rating of 1469 (Division 1) in TopCoder. Handle: CLown1331. [link]
- · Solved around 2800 problems in various online judges. [link]

PROJECTS

Project Renegade

September 2017

- · An FPS game Android Platform. Developed as University Third year final project. Technologies used: Unity3d, C#, Blender. [link]
- \cdot Lead the development team and executed the development process.
- · Task distribution and help team members to complete their task in time.
- · Developed the Gameplay system, UI System, AI System.
- · Developed tools for the level designer to quickly and easily create gameplay elements.

Coder Ranklist September 2020 - Present

- · A system to aggregate competitive programming profile performance for easier evaluations of overall performance . [link]
- · Technologies Used: Nodejs, Express, Redis, MongoDB, Heroku.
- · Designed and implemented a queue-based system, using Redis to aggregate competitive programming profile performance.